ANDREW J. MORRISON

ajmorrison@ucdavis.edu github.com/andjmorrison linkedin.com/in/andmorrison

Summary of Qualifications

Data Analyst passionate about condensing complex data into *meaningful* stories with data-wrangling and visualization. Demonstrated organizational, communication, and technical experience in academic settings. Enthusiasm for technical problem solving, conflict resolution, creativity, and collaboration. Self-starter, excited to develop new systems and improve workflows.

Skills

Tools: Python (Pandas, Matplotlib/Plotly, Flask, SQL-Alchemy/Pymongo, SKLearn, Keras/TF), Git (Github, GitLab),

JavaScript (D3, Plotly, Leaflet, Mapbox), HTML (Bootstrap), R (Shiny), Tableau

Databases: SQL, MongoDB, GCP/AWS **Languages:** Intermediate Spanish

Projects

r/nba Game Threads: ETL | https://github.com/andjmorrison/etl project

- -Compiled unique dataset merging NBA player statistics/shot-placement with Reddit Game Thread data
- -Scraped data from multiple APIs (NBA API, PRAW)
- -Loaded data into remote mongoDB after data-wrangling, merge, and cleanup processes

More Buckets | https://github.com/andjmorrison/mo buckets

- -Dashboard visualizing NBA Player statistics and shot distribution (Flask, JavaScript, Plotly)
- -Aggregated data from both APIs and remote noSQL database to form static API using Flask
- -Implemented machine-learning algorithm to predict player positions (SK-Learn, Keras)

URL Verifier

- -Script to verify URL accuracy in bibliographic records at UC Davis Law Library (Pandas, Requests)
- -Implement alternative solution to proprietary database lacking functionality

Education and Training

Data Analysis and Visualization, UC Davis

Certificate Program (2019)

- -6-month program focused on developing skills in data analysis, visualization, and database management
- -Projects using: Python, JavaScript, SQL/noSQL, Git, Tableau, R, VBA, Machine-Learning, Big Data

University of California, Berkeley

Bachelor of Arts, History with Honors (2012)

- -Drafted original thesis on Guatemalan National Police utilizing newly-created digital archive
- -Compiled finding aid for Archivo General de Centroamerica under Apprenticeship for Anthropology Dept.

Experience

UC Davis Continuing and Professional Education—Trilogy Education (Sacramento, CA)

Teaching Assistant for Data Analysis and Data Visualization (2020-Present)

- -Guide students in projects using variety of programming languages (Python, SQL, JavaScript, R, Git, VBA)
- -Maintain remote repository for course materials and coordinate project grading
- -Assist in troubleshooting and debugging student projects

UC Davis Mabie Law Library (Davis, CA)

Acquisitions/Circulation Assistant, Serials Lead, Student Supervisor (2015-Present)

- -Department accounts payable, accounts receivable, account resolution, financial analysis
- -Record and maintain all serials/government documents for Law Library in library database
- -Supervise and hire student library employees
- -Operate public service desk and provide support for broad range of clients, resolve and escalate problems
- -Plan, organize, and send shipments to UC binding and storage facilities
- -Added online availability for 4,000+ items within catalog for ease of use
- -Spearheaded reorganization of Archives and implemented clearly defined procedures
- -Expanded records for 10,000+ stored items to increase public accessibility

North Regional Library Facility (Richmond, CA)

Library Assistant (2013-2015)

- -Oversaw public service desk; facilitated in-person and remote requests for patrons
- -Copy-cataloged new material, including monographs and serials, Special Collections, foreign language, maps
- -Managed existing database records according to AACR2/RDA bibliographic, departmental guidelines
- -Prepared material for digital lending to affiliated patrons

Main Gardner Stacks, Doe Library (Berkeley, CA)

Student Library Employee (2012-2013)

- -Co-managed NRLF storage project and increased weekly shipments
- -Trained new student staff in NRLF shipment operations